<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CrispLab</title>
    <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://CrispLab.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>CrispLab</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>CC by-nd-nc 4.0; 2019</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://CrispLab.github.io/img/website%20icon.jpg</url>
      <title>CrispLab</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond the gene: epigenetic and cis-regulatory targets offer new breeding potential for the future</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/crisp-beyond-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/crisp-beyond-2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enzymes degraded under high light maintain proteostasis by transcriptional regulation in Arabidopsis</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/li-enzymes-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/li-enzymes-2021/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Current status and prospects of plant genome editing in Australia</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/zhang-current-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/zhang-current-2021/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic and epigenetic variation in transposable element expression responses to abiotic stress in maize</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/liang-genetic-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/liang-genetic-2021/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applying cis-regulatory codes to predict conserved and variable heat and cold stress response in maize</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/zhou-applying-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/zhou-applying-2021/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the regulatory potential of transposable elements using chromatin accessibility profiles of maize transposons</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/noshay-assessing-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/noshay-assessing-2021/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stable unmethylated DNA demarcates expressed genes and their cis-regulatory space in plant genomes</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/crisp-stable-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/crisp-stable-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic and epigenetic contributions to variation in transposable element expression responses to abiotic stress in maize</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/liang-genetic-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/liang-genetic-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cis-regulatory elements within TEs can influence expression of nearby maize genes</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/noshay-cis-regulatory-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/noshay-cis-regulatory-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD position available on crop epigenomics and enhancers</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/post/phd_position/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 17:36:36 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/post/phd_position/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have a funded PhD scholarship opportunity in the lab. Check out the details in this post or get in contact for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Scholarship is officially listed on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://graduate-school.uq.edu.au/phd-scholarships-science&#34;&gt;UQ Graduate School page&lt;/a&gt; search for Peter Crisp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The position is a fully funded PhD scholarship for a domestic or international student (stipend + tuition + health cover). More details on the scholarship scheme can be found here on the UQ Graduate School &lt;a href=&#34;https://scholarships.uq.edu.au/scholarship/earmarked-scholarships-support-category-1-project-grants#qt-scholarship_tabs-foundation-tabs-1&#34;&gt;Earmarked Scholarship page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full description below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Title: Using epigenomics to discover hidden genetic control elements for crop improvement&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sustainable, productive agricultural processes are essential for tackling the challenges of tomorrow’s world. The ability to optimise beneficial agricultural traits depends on the precise control of genes in a crop plant’s enormous genome. Yet, identifying valuable gene control regions – also known as cis-regulatory elements – is like looking for needles in a haystack. The location of these regions is often not obvious and current detection technologies are impractically expensive and intensive. This PhD project aims to refine and implement a new technology, based on epigenomic profiling, that is expected to facilitate rapid and cost-effective discovery of all the control regions in a genome, enhancing our understanding of crop genomes and unlocking new avenues for agricultural improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this PhD project, the successful candidate will create and analyse genome-wide maps of candidate gene control regions (cis-regulatory elements) using epigenome profiling and next generation sequencing in cereal crops; for instance, barley, sorghum, wheat, rice, and maize. The functionality of select regulatory elements will be tested using traditional reporter assays in combination with massively parallel reporter assays (eg STARR-seq). This project will test our ability to utilise these regulatory maps to create new traits, by gene editing select regulatory elements using CRISPR. There will be opportunities to work in model species such as Nicotiana benthamiana as well as translational work in crops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Candidates should have an Honours degree, Masters by research, Masters by coursework or equivalent in Plant Biology or Plant Genetics, Biotechnology, Molecular Biology or a related field. Experience in cloning or plant transformation will be highly regarded. Candidates interested in learning and performing bioinformatic analyses are encouraged to apply; prior computational experience not required. Please contact the Dr Peter Crisp to check on this project&amp;rsquo;s availability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*The successful candidate must commence by Research Quarter 1, 2021. You should apply at least 3 months prior to the research quarter commencement date. Due to time constraints, only Domestic and on-shore International applicants will be considered.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lab Opened</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/post/lab_open/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 17:33:57 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/post/lab_open/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There has been a lot going on lately&amp;hellip; including the grand opening of the Lab. We are here! Excited to be at UQ. Located in the John Hines Building, St Lucia.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenetic Regulation of ABA-Induced Transcriptional Responses in Maize</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/vendramin-epigenetic-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/vendramin-epigenetic-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meta Gene Regulatory Networks in Maize Highlight Functionally Relevant Regulatory Interactions</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/zhou-meta-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/zhou-meta-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular and physiological responses during thermal acclimation of leaf photosynthesis and respiration in rice</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/rashid-molecular-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/rashid-molecular-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimization of multiplexed CRISPR/Cas9 system for highly efficient genome editing in Setaria viridis</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/weiss-optimization-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/weiss-optimization-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variation and inheritance of small RNAs in maize inbreds and F1 hybrids</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/crisp-variation-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/crisp-variation-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Population-level analysis reveals the widespread occurrence and phenotypic consequence of DNA methylation variation not tagged by genetic variation in maize</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/xu-population-level-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/xu-population-level-2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crop epigenetics and epigenomics</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/project/crop_epigenetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 21:35:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/project/crop_epigenetics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;epigenetic-inheritance&#34;&gt;Epigenetic inheritance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technological advances in sequencing throughput and epigenome editing are enabling us to now readdress fundamental unanswered questions concerning the inheritance, stability, variation and functional relevance of epialleles in large crop genomes. Such investigations are having a profound impact on our understanding and the utility of epigenetic information for agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major focus of our research is characterizing the inheritance patterns of DNA methylation and other epialleles, which contribute to the unexpected and non-mendelian inheritance of traits. We recently studied in detail maize plants that were passed through tissue culture (eg for transformation) and found accumulation of targeted, heritable changes in DNA methylation at unstable loci ​(Han et al., 2018)​. We are also continuing to study the inheritance of DNA methylation over generations in maize populations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast to maize, clonal horticultural species, like apple, present a unique opportunity to study and potentially exploit epigenomic regulation and inheritance within a single genetic lineage. We are tracking the inheritance and variation of epialleles in clonal apple lineages, which could relate to spontaneous variation and trait stability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;epigenome-engineering-in-monocot-crops&#34;&gt;Epigenome engineering in monocot crops&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Natural variation is a powerful resource for investigating the role of DNA methylation. However, using epigenome engineering tools including &lt;strong&gt;CRISPR&lt;/strong&gt;, we are working to generate germplasm with far greater levels of epigenetic variation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, in crops species with large genomes, germplasm with even moderate reductions in DNA methylation are not available, severely limiting our ability to study the role of epialleles. We are also implementing tools for locus-specific epigenome editing in monocots. Ultimately, reengineering the levels of methylation will allow us to answer fundamental questions about the function of methylation throughout crop genomes. Future applications also include using epigenome engineering and synthetic biology to modulate epialleles for crop improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cryptic-epigenetic-variation&#34;&gt;Cryptic epigenetic variation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In large crop genomes there are many silent loci, including protein coding genes, which are associated with DNA methylation ​(Eichten et al., 2013)​. These loci may represent cryptic variation. The extent to which these loci are expressed in a subset of members of a species is relatively unexplored in crop genomics due to the historical costs of sequencing technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are identifying cryptic variation in barley using comparative (epi)genomics in combination with the introduction of epigenome engineering tools. In the longer term we will use these varieties to develop Epigenetic Recombinant Inbred Lines (epiRILs) to uncover cryptic epialleles associated with trait variation through activating silent parts of the genome.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenomics and stress resilience</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/project/stress/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 20:37:49 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/project/stress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our research focuses on the interface between epigenomics and plant memory. This research area addresses key challenges identified in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://plantsummit.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/plantsciencedecadalvision10-18-13.pdf&#34;&gt;decadal vision for Plant Sciences&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The possible roles of epigenetics in environmental responses are hotly debated. While plants clearly retain some memories of past experiences, the extent to which the environment leads to heritable changes in the epigenome is unresolved ​(Mirouze and Paszkowski, 2011)​. Despite expectations, the epigenome, in particular DNA methylation, is particularly resistant to many environmental perturbations ​(Crisp et al., 2016). We have demonstrated that DNA methylation is unresponsive to multiple stresses ​(Ganguly et al., 2017, 2018)​. One possibility is that rapid recovery mechanisms preclude lasting imprints of stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cryptic-stress-resilience-epialleles&#34;&gt;Cryptic stress resilience epialleles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While DNA methylation may be relatively impervious to stress, beneficial but non-essential stress resilience alleles may have become silenced by DNA methylation over time. We hypothesise that stress resilience traits may be enriched among the cryptic epiallele variants. We aim to identify and characterize cryptic stress resilience traits using comparative genomics tools and epiRIL populations is crops such as barley and sorghum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stress-recovery-in-crops&#34;&gt;Stress recovery in crops&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a second novel avenue towards enhancing stress resilience, we are investigating the tension between plant stress memory and recovery. This is an on going colaboration with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://biology.anu.edu.au/research/groups/pogson-group-chloroplast-nuclear-signalling-light-drought-and-carotenoids&#34;&gt;Pogson Lab, ANU&lt;/a&gt;. We have found that the transcriptome recovers from light-stress with incredible speed ​(Crisp et al., 2017)​. Our future interest is in examining whether various crops, including C3 (barley) and C4 (maize), also have mechanisms for rapid transcriptome recovery from light-stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extending prior work, we are constructing gene regulatory networks (GRNs) using RNA-seq from light-stress recovery time courses to identify factors important for both rapid deactivation of stress responses and for re-activation of growth and productivity. These factors; for instance, key transcription factors or signaling pathway genes, will be targeted for detailed reverse genetic characterization.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenome guided crop improvement - distilling the Functional Genome</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/project/umr-distilling-functional-elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 23:18:31 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/project/umr-distilling-functional-elements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using epigenomic signatures to discover &amp;lsquo;functional&amp;rsquo; and cis-regulatory elements in large crop genomes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many crops have incredibly large genomes, ranging from the modest 730 megabases (Mb) sorghum genome to the massive 17,000 Mb hexaploid wheat genome. Yet, recently developed technologies have enabled even the larger genomes to be completely sequenced and have provided unprecedented insights into the number, form and function of their genes and the landscape of their chromosomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The identification of sequences of protein-coding genes and non-coding RNAs, with their associated promoter, terminator and intron sequences, has become relatively straightforward and accurate. However, it is becoming increasingly clear that there are other regions within the genome that play an enormous role in regulating and coordinating gene expression. These regions are not easily identified bioinformatically, as they are often located a considerable distance from their target genes and do not have readily-distinguishable sequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together with collaborators (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.waterhouse-lab.com/main/index_lab.html&#34;&gt;Waterhouse lab&lt;/a&gt;, QUT, Australia; &lt;a href=&#34;http://schmitzlab.genetics.uga.edu/&#34;&gt;Schmitz Lab&lt;/a&gt;, UGA, USA; &lt;a href=&#34;https://maizeumn.github.io/&#34;&gt;Springer lab&lt;/a&gt;, UMN, USA ), we are developing a novel methodology to efficiently and affordably identify gene control regions, known as ​cis​-regulatory elements, in large genome crops. Our preliminary analysis, together with prior studies in plants, suggests that ​cis-​elements are predictably marked by a distinct lack of DNA methylation; we term these “unmethylated regions” (UMRs) ​(Crisp et al., 2019)​. We are testing the hypothesis that DNA methylation profiles can be used to efficiently identify ​cis​-elements in plant genomes. Key elements can then be targeted for crop improvement using CRISPR and other genome editing approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this project, we are leveraging the resources of ​N. benthamiana (tobacco), which is peerless in its amenability to functional validation work (eg CRISPR) and transient expression analysis; in combination with methylC-seq, ATAC-seq, STARR-seq and RNA-seq.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project initially focused on ​N. benthamiana and maize, and is now expanding to realise the tremendous opportunities many other crop species including in sorghum, barley and wheat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Opening Feb 2020</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/post/lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 22:52:24 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/post/lab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The lab will be opening at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uq.edu.au/&#34;&gt;University of Queensland&lt;/a&gt;, St Lucia Campus, in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://agriculture.uq.edu.au/&#34;&gt;School of Agriculture and Food Sciences&lt;/a&gt; beginning Feb 2020. We will be looking for students! Contact me for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Decay: A Transgenerational Epigenetic Decline in Vigor and Viability Triggered in Backcross Populations of Teosinte with Maize</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/xue-hybrid-2019-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/xue-hybrid-2019-1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring the interplay between transposable element families and DNA methylation in maize</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/noshay-monitoring-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/noshay-monitoring-2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid decay: a transgenerational epigenetic decline in vigor and viability triggered in backcross populations of teosinte with maize</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/xue-hybrid-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/xue-hybrid-2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opportunities to Use DNA Methylation to Distil Functional Elements in Large Crop Genomes</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/crisp-opportunities-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/crisp-opportunities-2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RNA Polymerase II Read-Through Promotes Expression of Neighboring Genes in SAL1-PAP-XRN Retrograde Signaling</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/crisp-rna-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/crisp-rna-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heritable Epigenomic Changes to the Maize Methylome Resulting from Tissue Culture</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/han-heritable-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/han-heritable-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintenance of pre-existing DNA methylation states through recurring excess-light stress</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/ganguly-maintenance-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/ganguly-maintenance-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeted epigenomic changes to the maize methylome resulting from tissue culture</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/han-targeted-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/han-targeted-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Maize Methylome</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/noshay-maize-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/noshay-maize-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A chloroplast retrograde signal, 3’-phosphoadenosine 5’-phosphate, acts as a secondary messenger in abscisic acid signaling in stomatal closure and germination</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/pornsiriwong-chloroplast-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/pornsiriwong-chloroplast-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapid recovery gene downregulation during excess-light stress and recovery in Arabidopsis</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/crisp-rapid-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/crisp-rapid-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Arabidopsis DNA methylome is stable under transgenerational drought stress</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/ganguly-arabidopsis-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/ganguly-arabidopsis-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncoupling high light responses from singlet oxygen retrograde signaling and spatial-temporal systemic acquired acclimation in Arabidopsis</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/carmody-uncoupling-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/carmody-uncoupling-2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconsidering plant memory: Intersections between stress recovery, RNA turnover, and epigenetics</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/crisp-reconsidering-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/crisp-reconsidering-2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning the Languages of the Chloroplast: Retrograde Signaling and Beyond</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/chan-learning-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/chan-learning-2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic suppression of plant development and chloroplast biogenesis via the Snowy Cotyledon 3 and Phytochrome B pathways</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/ganguly-genetic-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/ganguly-genetic-2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grafting in Arabidopsis</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/bainbridge-grafting-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/bainbridge-grafting-2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subset of heat-shock transcription factors required for the early response of Arabidopsis to excess light</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/jung-subset-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/jung-subset-2013/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evidence for a SAL1-PAP Chloroplast Retrograde Pathway That Functions in Drought and High Light Signaling in Arabidopsis</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/estavillo-evidence-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/estavillo-evidence-2011/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Novel fry1 Allele Reveals the Existence of a Mutant Phenotype Unrelated to 5′-textgreater3′ Exoribonuclease (XRN) Activities in Arabidopsis thaliana Roots</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/hirsch-novel-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/hirsch-novel-2011/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chloroplast-to-nucleus communication</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/chan-chloroplast-nucleus-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/chan-chloroplast-nucleus-2010/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regulation of Carotenoid Composition and Shoot Branching in Arabidopsis by a Chromatin Modifying Histone Methyltransferase, SDG8</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/cazzonelli-regulation-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/cazzonelli-regulation-2009/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
