<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CrispLab</title>
    <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://CrispLab.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>CrispLab</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>CC by-nd-nc 4.0; 2019</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://CrispLab.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>CrispLab</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variation and inheritance of small RNAs in maize inbreds and F1 hybrids</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/crisp-variation-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/crisp-variation-2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crop epigenetics and epigenomics</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/project/crop_epigenetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 21:35:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/project/crop_epigenetics/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;epigenetic-inheritance&#34;&gt;Epigenetic inheritance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technological advances in sequencing throughput and epigenome editing are enabling us to now readdress fundamental unanswered questions concerning the inheritance, stability, variation and functional relevance of epialleles in large crop genomes. Such investigations are having a profound impact on our understanding and the utility of epigenetic information for agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A major focus of our research is characterizing the inheritance patterns of DNA methylation and other epialleles, which contribute to the unexpected and non-mendelian inheritance of traits. We recently studied in detail maize plants that were passed through tissue culture (eg for transformation) and found accumulation of targeted, heritable changes in DNA methylation at unstable loci ​(Han et al., 2018)​. We are also continuing to study the inheritance of DNA methylation over generations in maize populations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast to maize, clonal horticultural species, like apple, present a unique opportunity to study and potentially exploit epigenomic regulation and inheritance within a single genetic lineage. We are tracking the inheritance and variation of epialleles in clonal apple lineages, which could relate to spontaneous variation and trait stability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;epigenome-engineering-in-monocot-crops&#34;&gt;Epigenome engineering in monocot crops&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Natural variation is a powerful resource for investigating the role of DNA methylation. However, using epigenome engineering tools including &lt;strong&gt;CRISPR&lt;/strong&gt;, we are working to generate germplasm with far greater levels of epigenetic variation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, in crops species with large genomes, germplasm with even moderate reductions in DNA methylation are not available, severely limiting our ability to study the role of epialleles. We are also implementing tools for locus-specific epigenome editing in monocots. Ultimately, reengineering the levels of methylation will allow us to answer fundamental questions about the function of methylation throughout crop genomes. Future applications also include using epigenome engineering and synthetic biology to modulate epialleles for crop improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cryptic-epigenetic-variation&#34;&gt;Cryptic epigenetic variation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In large crop genomes there are many silent loci, including protein coding genes, which are associated with DNA methylation ​(Eichten et al., 2013)​. These loci may represent cryptic variation. The extent to which these loci are expressed in a subset of members of a species is relatively unexplored in crop genomics due to the historical costs of sequencing technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are identifying cryptic variation in barley using comparative (epi)genomics in combination with the introduction of epigenome engineering tools. In the longer term we will use these varieties to develop Epigenetic Recombinant Inbred Lines (epiRILs) to uncover cryptic epialleles associated with trait variation through activating silent parts of the genome.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenomics and stress resilience</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/project/stress/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 20:37:49 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/project/stress/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Our research focuses on the interface between epigenomics and plant memory. This research area addresses key challenges identified in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://plantsummit.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/plantsciencedecadalvision10-18-13.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;decadal vision for Plant Sciences&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The possible roles of epigenetics in environmental responses are hotly debated. While plants clearly retain some memories of past experiences, the extent to which the environment leads to heritable changes in the epigenome is unresolved ​(Mirouze and Paszkowski, 2011)​. Despite expectations, the epigenome, in particular DNA methylation, is particularly resistant to many environmental perturbations ​(Crisp et al., 2016). We have demonstrated that DNA methylation is unresponsive to multiple stresses ​(Ganguly et al., 2017, 2018)​. One possibility is that rapid recovery mechanisms preclude lasting imprints of stress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cryptic-stress-resilience-epialleles&#34;&gt;Cryptic stress resilience epialleles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While DNA methylation may be relatively impervious to stress, beneficial but non-essential stress resilience alleles may have become silenced by DNA methylation over time. We hypothesise that stress resilience traits may be enriched among the cryptic epiallele variants. We aim to identify and characterize cryptic stress resilience traits using comparative genomics tools and epiRIL populations is crops such as barley and sorghum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;stress-recovery-in-crops&#34;&gt;Stress recovery in crops&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a second novel avenue towards enhancing stress resilience, we are investigating the tension between plant stress memory and recovery. This is an on going colaboration with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://biology.anu.edu.au/research/groups/pogson-group-chloroplast-nuclear-signalling-light-drought-and-carotenoids&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pogson Lab, ANU&lt;/a&gt;. We have found that the transcriptome recovers from light-stress with incredible speed ​(Crisp et al., 2017)​. Our future interest is in examining whether various crops, including C3 (barley) and C4 (maize), also have mechanisms for rapid transcriptome recovery from light-stress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extending prior work, we are constructing gene regulatory networks (GRNs) using RNA-seq from light-stress recovery time courses to identify factors important for both rapid deactivation of stress responses and for re-activation of growth and productivity. These factors; for instance, key transcription factors or signaling pathway genes, will be targeted for detailed reverse genetic characterization.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distilling the Functional Genome</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/project/umr-distilling-functional-elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 23:18:31 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/project/umr-distilling-functional-elements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using epigenomic signatures to discover &amp;lsquo;functional&amp;rsquo; and regulatory elements in large crop genomes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many crops have incredibly large genomes, ranging from the modest 730 megabases (Mb) sorghum genome to the massive 17,000 Mb hexaploid wheat genome. Yet, recently developed technologies have enabled even the larger genomes to be completely sequenced and have provided unprecedented insights into the number, form and function of their genes and the landscape of their chromosomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The identification of sequences of protein-coding genes and non-coding RNAs, with their associated promoter, terminator and intron sequences, has become relatively straightforward and accurate. However, it is becoming increasingly clear that there are other regions within the genome that play an enormous role in regulating and coordinating gene expression. These regions are not easily identified bioinformatically, as they are often located a considerable distance from their target genes and do not have readily-distinguishable sequences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Together with collaborators (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.waterhouse-lab.com/main/index_lab.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Waterhouse lab&lt;/a&gt;, QUT, Australia; &lt;a href=&#34;http://schmitzlab.genetics.uga.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Schmitz Lab&lt;/a&gt;, UGA, USA; &lt;a href=&#34;https://maizeumn.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Springer lab&lt;/a&gt;, UMN, USA ), we are developing a novel methodology to efficiently and affordably identify gene control regions, known as ​cis​-regulatory elements, in large genome crops. Our preliminary analysis, together with prior studies in plants, suggests that ​cis-​elements are predictably marked by a distinct lack of DNA methylation; we term these “unmethylated regions” (UMRs) ​(Crisp et al., 2019)​. We are testing the hypothesis that DNA methylation profiles can be used to efficiently identify ​cis​-elements in plant genomes. Key elements can then be targeted for crop improvement using CRISPR and other genome editing approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this project, we are leveraging the resources of ​N. benthamiana (tobacco), which is peerless in its amenability to functional validation work (eg CRISPR) and transient expression analysis; in combination with methylC-seq, ATAC-seq, STARR-seq and RNA-seq.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project will initially focus on ​N. benthamiana and maize, however, there are tremendous opportunities for direct application in many crop species including work in sorghum and barley.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Opening Feb 2020</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/post/lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 22:52:24 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/post/lab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The lab will be opening at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uq.edu.au/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;University of Queensland&lt;/a&gt;, St Lucia Campus, in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://agriculture.uq.edu.au/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;School of Agriculture and Food Sciences&lt;/a&gt; beginning Feb 2020. We will be looking for students! Contact me for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Decay: A Transgenerational Epigenetic Decline in Vigor and Viability Triggered in Backcross Populations of Teosinte with Maize</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/xue-hybrid-2019-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/xue-hybrid-2019-1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring the interplay between transposable element families and DNA methylation in maize</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/noshay-monitoring-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/noshay-monitoring-2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid decay: a transgenerational epigenetic decline in vigor and viability triggered in backcross populations of teosinte with maize</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/xue-hybrid-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/xue-hybrid-2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opportunities to Use DNA Methylation to Distil Functional Elements in Large Crop Genomes</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/crisp-opportunities-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/crisp-opportunities-2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RNA Polymerase II Read-Through Promotes Expression of Neighboring Genes in SAL1-PAP-XRN Retrograde Signaling</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/crisp-rna-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/crisp-rna-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heritable Epigenomic Changes to the Maize Methylome Resulting from Tissue Culture</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/han-heritable-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/han-heritable-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintenance of pre-existing DNA methylation states through recurring excess-light stress</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/ganguly-maintenance-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/ganguly-maintenance-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeted epigenomic changes to the maize methylome resulting from tissue culture</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/han-targeted-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/han-targeted-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Maize Methylome</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/noshay-maize-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/noshay-maize-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A chloroplast retrograde signal, 3’-phosphoadenosine 5’-phosphate, acts as a secondary messenger in abscisic acid signaling in stomatal closure and germination</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/pornsiriwong-chloroplast-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/pornsiriwong-chloroplast-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapid recovery gene downregulation during excess-light stress and recovery in Arabidopsis</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/crisp-rapid-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/crisp-rapid-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Arabidopsis DNA methylome is stable under transgenerational drought stress</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/ganguly-arabidopsis-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/ganguly-arabidopsis-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncoupling high light responses from singlet oxygen retrograde signaling and spatial-temporal systemic acquired acclimation in Arabidopsis</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/carmody-uncoupling-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/carmody-uncoupling-2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconsidering plant memory: Intersections between stress recovery, RNA turnover, and epigenetics</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/crisp-reconsidering-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/crisp-reconsidering-2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning the Languages of the Chloroplast: Retrograde Signaling and Beyond</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/chan-learning-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/chan-learning-2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic suppression of plant development and chloroplast biogenesis via the Snowy Cotyledon 3 and Phytochrome B pathways</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/ganguly-genetic-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/ganguly-genetic-2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grafting in Arabidopsis</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/bainbridge-grafting-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/bainbridge-grafting-2014/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subset of heat-shock transcription factors required for the early response of Arabidopsis to excess light</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/jung-subset-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/jung-subset-2013/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evidence for a SAL1-PAP Chloroplast Retrograde Pathway That Functions in Drought and High Light Signaling in Arabidopsis</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/estavillo-evidence-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/estavillo-evidence-2011/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Novel fry1 Allele Reveals the Existence of a Mutant Phenotype Unrelated to 5′-textgreater3′ Exoribonuclease (XRN) Activities in Arabidopsis thaliana Roots</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/hirsch-novel-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/hirsch-novel-2011/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chloroplast-to-nucleus communication</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/chan-chloroplast-nucleus-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/chan-chloroplast-nucleus-2010/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regulation of Carotenoid Composition and Shoot Branching in Arabidopsis by a Chromatin Modifying Histone Methyltransferase, SDG8</title>
      <link>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/cazzonelli-regulation-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CrispLab.github.io/publication/cazzonelli-regulation-2009/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
